sixminutestosuccess.com 2017-12-02

# Privacy Policy - Proctor Gallagher Institute

Proctor Gallagher Institute (the “Company”) is dedicated to protecting privacy while using the services of [www.proctorgallagherinstitute.com](http://www.proctorgallagherinstitute.com/) and its affiliated websites (the “Site”).  This privacy policy statement explains information collection and use practices for the Site. By accessing the Site, you are agreeing with and consenting to the data collection and use practices described in this privacy policy. This privacy policy statement expressly incorporates and is subject to the Terms of Use (“TOU”) for the Site, which may be separately accessed via a hypertext link located on its homepage. The provisions, terms and conditions set forth in the TOU shall supersede, govern and control in the event of any actual or potential inconsistency or conflict with the contents of this privacy policy statement.

**PERSONAL DATA COLLECTION**

You may be asked to provide the Company with information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you (“Personal Data”), if necessary, to carry out a transaction or other service that you have requested in connection with use of the Site. The Personal Data the Company gathers, if necessary, may include your name, title, company or organization name, e-mail address, work phone, work or home address, information about your job function, information about your company and credit card information, as well as additional information that may be necessary to provide services offered on or in connection with the Site.

The Company may additionally collect certain information about your visit, such as the name of the Internet service provider and the Internet Protocol (IP) address through which you accessed the Internet; the date and time you accessed the Site; the pages that you have accessed while at the Site and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to the Site. This information is used to help the Company improve the Site, analyze trends and administer the Site.

In order to avoid your e-mail address or other personal information from being gathered and used by others for inappropriate and harmful purposes, the Company strongly advises that you use exercise extreme caution when posting your e-mail address or other personal information to newsgroups, chats, listings or other public forums on the Site or any other website.

**PERSONAL DATA USE**

The Personal Data collected on the Site will be used to operate the Site and to provide service(s) and/or carry out the transaction(s) you have requested or authorized in connection with the Site.

The Company may use Personal Data to provide you with customer service for Site improvements, any related products or services or to otherwise customize the Site to your particular preferences or interests.

The Company may use personal information or Personal Data to provide you with important information about the products or services that you are using, to inform or inquire about products, services or matters related to the Site, which may include updates and notifications. Additionally, we may send you information about other products, services and/or share information with partners and affiliates so that they may send you information about certain products and services.

When you sign up for or agree to receive promotional e-mail or other offers made in connection with or via use of the Site, the Company may use customized links or similar technologies to track e-mail links that you click. The Company may associate that information with your personal information or Personal Data in order to provide you more focused e-mail communications, use of the Site or other services and information related to, offered on or available through the Site. The Company will provide means to unsubscribe to e-mail communications that allows you to stop delivery of that type of communication.

We may disclose your personal information and/or Personal Data if required to do so by law or in good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on the Site or the Company; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of the Site or the Company; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of employees or agents, user of this Site’s products or services, or members of the public.

Personal information and Personal Data collected on the Site may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which the Company or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities. By using this Site, you consent to any such transfer or information outside of your country.

**CONTROL OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

Except as otherwise described in this statement, personal information and Personal Data provided to the Company with regard to use of the Site will not be shared outside of this Site and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates without your permission.

The Company may send out periodic e-mails informing you of certain services or products offered by it, its subsidiaries and affiliates, concerning technical services or security issues related to a product or service you requested or otherwise related to your use of the Site, or confirming a requested product or service related to the Site. Contact with the customer is an intrinsic part of the product or service being offered. You will not be able to unsubscribe to these e-mails as they are considered an essential part of the product(s) or service(s) you have chosen.

**PERSONAL DATA SECURITY**

The Company is committed to protecting the security of your Personal Data. The Company, through its selected service providers, uses a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information and Personal Data from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

**USE OF COOKIES**

The Company may use cookies on this Site to ensure the integrity of the registration process, if required, and to personalize the Site. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser settings to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of this Site or other websites you visit.

**MODIFICATIONS TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT**

The Company may occasionally modify this privacy policy statement. When this is done, the Company will also revise the “last updated” date at the top of the privacy policy statement. The Company encourages you to periodically review this private policy statement to stay informed as to how the Company is helping to protect the Personal Data it collects. Your continued use of the Site constitutes your agreement to this privacy policy statement, its terms, conditions and any updates thereto.  Updates to this privacy policy statement will be posted online only.  You will not be sent e-mail or other forms of notification that updates to this privacy policy statement have been made.  Accordingly, you are advised to review this privacy policy statement periodically for updates.

**CONTACT INFORMATION**

We welcome your comments regarding this privacy policy statement.  You may contact us via e-mail at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d5b6a0a6a1bab8b0a7a6b0a7a3bcb6b095a5a7bab6a1baa7b2b4b9b9b4b2bdb0a7fbb6bab8) or by U.S. Mail at Proctor Gallagher Institute – Privacy Policy Comments, 5010 E Shea Blvd, Suite 255, Scottsdale, AZ 85254.
